If you're Type B, you need to take care.
If you continue to let it be,
it could become a serious,
even life-threatening, situation.
Turn it off!
But this program will reveal
the solution in one fell swoop!
This TV is sick!
It's really nothing
to be scared about...
How about taking a bath?
Am I gonna die too?
Hah?
What are you talking about?
You're only 6 years old!
Sorry!
I dunno about tomorrow.
It's different than a sacrifice. Something's off.
I don't think it's like some penalty game.
So, why? I don't get it at all.
I'm a little bit unsatisfied, but your presence
right now is more than just important.
There's no such thing in this world
as something never-ending.
Crying isn't painful, it's love's sweet drops, sweet drops!
I want to keep dreaming forever, ya know?
I want to be more kind, ya know?
As long as I’m with you, I’m happy.
Girls sure are strong, ya know?
But sometimes we're weak, ya know?
Our wish is to be happy, happy, happy!
And those days will be happy, too!
Just wanna make you happy!
See you later!
If I don't decide on the next nursery
school soon, I'll be up the creek!
I've heard that smart people
enter huge companies
that have a day-care
center on the premises.
But what country are
we talking about here?!
Kawachi-san!
Hey!
Kawachi-san, did you get a girlfriend?
What?!
You're going home early
all the time these days...
Well, it's not that.
You always used to take
the last train, right?
And last year, sales went through
the roof because of you,
but at this rate...
Those aren't figures that can be made
through just enthusiasm or tenacity.
I was lucky.
After all, my name's Daikichi...
[ Note: Daikichi means "excellent luck" ]
Kawachi-san!
Wait!
I'll take that.
Thanks!
You're going to the 4th floor, right?
Yep. So you guys doing well, as always?
Not this year.
In fact, this guy was just
putting the pressure on me.
Look how my hairline's receding.
After you've achieved results
once, it's tough, huh?
Um, Gotou-san, you really have a child?
Just because I'm short, you have doubts?
No, it's just you're so thin, I can't
imagine where you stored the baby...
I can't remember anymore, either.
He's two already.
Thanks. Just put 'em down here.
I'll go with you.
Oh, I can manage.
All right...
See you!
She's as powerful as ever, y'know?
If only Gotou-san had stayed in sales...
She's worked here years longer than me,
but after getting pregnant,
she requested a demotion,
so she could go home at a set time.
Everyone in the company
was talking about her...
How long are you going
to take care of her?!
No time frame has really
been settled on...
Rin-chan, huh?
She's been wetting the bed these days.
And I can tell that it
really embarrasses her.
Maybe it's an emotional thing.
But you'd be surprised
how much kids sweat,
though not as much in
the fall or winter.
The number of times they
pee increases then.
I always used to be told...
Pee before going to bed.
Her mother must've had her reasons.
I'd ask her if I could...
But mothers are important, aren't they?
If you're any kind of
man, never say die!
Hang in there!
What'd you play today?
I read picture books... and
had a staring contest...
Was it fun?
What's that for?
Rin, I'm gonna make dinner right away.
The moon's deflated, huh?
Mother-Child Health Record Book
Hello?
Well, how's it going?
I'm fine, sure...
I'm not asking about you.
Oh. She's good.
Wait a second, I thought you
didn't want to be involved.
You're the one that's
taking care of her,
so I can't help but be involved.
I'm gonna try to find a clue about
Rin-chan's mom this weekend,
so I'll be out your way.
I see... Then give me a call
when you reach the station.
Make sure you dress that
girl warmly enough.
Yeah... I'll invite Haruko, too.
It seems she's friendly with her girl.
We passed another car!
Looks like you're having a good time...
Yeah!
We're here.
Welcome back.
Rin-chan, thank you for coming!
Hey!
I'm sorry I don't have anything
that would please a small child.
She likes old people
stuff anyway. Right?
Are you done already?
Yeah.
Don't come crying to me
if you're hungry later.
I'm stuffed...
I'm sorry I couldn't finish.
I'm home!
Sorry I'm late!
That was awful!
What's with that annoying
mother and child?!
Big brother!
You seriously took
custody of this girl?!
Yeah...
And now the weather.
It's sunny and warm all
over the country today.
Temperatures in all regions are about
2 degrees higher than average
for this time of year,
making it pleasant weather everywhere.
I'm just going to the bathroom.
And now let's look at the
forecast for tomorrow.
I need to use the toilet!
I can't go with you sitting there!
Is she always like that?
No...
She's a lot more talkative at home.
She even had fun on the train,
acting like she was on a trip.
But waiting when we got here
were the people who were
all uptight at the funeral.
What are you accusing us of?!
Dope. If adults are in a bad mood, kids
think they're the ones they're mad at.
You're right...
It may have been that
way for you kids, too.
See?! Insensitive as you
are, you were the same way!
And Rin's smarter than you ever were!
Shut up, old man!
Rin-chan, you like cat's
cradle, don't you?
Come on, at least answer.
Yeah...
I'll give this one to you.
It's pretty...
Watch Aunty do it first, okay?
"Aunty"? You mean "Grandma", don't you?
You're not old enough to be my grandma!
My! What a good girl!
It's because her standard
for old age is crazy-high!
I'll go first, so watch me!
Huh? Did I do it wrong?
Huh?
This? A 4-step ladder.
My!
A 2-step ladder.
An airplane.
A slide.
A diamond!
That's amazing.
It's easy to do it with this yarn.
Did you make this?
That's right. I knitted
it from thin wool.
Doing that makes it the perfect weight,
more than just making
loops with woolen yarn.
I know! Since she's good with her
hands, I bet she can do beanbags, too!
You hook it around your
little finger like this...
L-Like this?
Yeah, that's it!
One, two, buckle my shoe. Three,
four, knock at the door...
What is this?! What the
heck is going on here?!
"What is this?!" Isn't
this what you wanted?!
Yes?!
Who is it?
Maybe Haruko-san.
Rin-chan!
These are pretty! What do you call them?
They're beanbags.
Thanks for coming today.
You do it like this?
Like this?
No problem.
Like this. And you sing
a song as you do it.
I'm really impressed that you can
juggle working and raising a child.
It's hard!
My husband doesn't help
in that regard at all.
Aunty taught me how to do it.
Who's your aunty?
Daikichi's mom.
Are you going to Grandpa's
house from now?
That's not Aunty, that's Grandma!
Yeah... I thought maybe I could
find a clue to Rin's mother.
Isn't this a pretty string?
That makes sense...
It's really easy to use.
After all, I think a
mother is important.
Maybe I can do it good, too...
Go like this, then this...
Huh?
Strange...
Grandpa, you should've
at least written a will.
Weren't you worried about Rin?!
A modem?
I'm back.
W-What's with that hair?!
She did it like Reina-chan's!
Come to think of it,
those clothes too...
These are Kazumi's!
Hah? Kazumi?
Mom, she can't wear old,
out-of-style clothes like that!
Look how nice she looks in them!
Well, I guess...
With her body type, they do become her.
This brings back memories.
So how was Grandpa's house?
These were from when you were 4, Kazumi.
I didn't find a single clue.
I see...
Well, even so, we shouldn't impatiently
ask Rin-chan about this and that.
You're doing your best.
We may have never told you this...
After you were born, Mom worked.
She hasn't been a housewife
the whole time...?
When she was pregnant with Kazumi,
she overdid it and had to
be hospitalized for a while.
When she returned to work,
Mom found there wasn't
a place for her anymore.
She was terribly depressed.
And Kazumi was so tiny
when she was born...
Mom often took off work and
came home early for you kids.
And what about Kazumi?
She made raising Kazumi
her first priority,
so she ended up as you can
see, arrogant and bossy!
How are you on time? Do you
want Dad to drop you off?
Nah, that's all right. We'll
still make it in time if we walk.
Can we come back again?
She says, "Can we come back again?"
Aunty will be here waiting for
you, so come back anytime.
Bye.
W-What are you talking about?!
What's wrong with wanting a grandchild?!
I'd take care of the baby...
I can't work and raise a
child at the same time!
For a woman, that's a huge loss!
Besides, I still wanna wear a
swimsuit and go out drinking...
Hey, Rin, did Grandpa have a computer?
Do you know what a computer is?
Yeah.
Did Grandpa use it?
The maid used it.
He had a maid?
The maid's name was Masako-san.
Mother-Child Health Record Book
Masako Yoshii
W-What was she like?
I don't remember so much...
I hate Masako-san...
She hated me and was always angry.
I was scared of her...
That's why I forgot about her.
I see.
It's a little late to be saying this,
but it's tough to work full-time
and raise a kid, isn't it?
You've got that right.
There's never a dull
moment, that's for sure.
Um, have you ever thought that
you were sacrificing yourself
by having a child, Gotou-san?
Are you referring to
my change in position?
Sorry. I know this is being rude, but...
Mmm, at the time, I thought
that was the best choice,
and it turned out all right,
so I have no problem with it.
But even if it was a sacrifice for me,
I wouldn't want to talk about it.
Because words have a strong power, see?
What do some people say,
the "spirit of language"?
Is that too abstract?
No...
I understand exactly what you mean!
Please tell me more about
kids again sometime.
Kawachi-kun, your child is
older than mine, isn't she?
I want you to teach me, Senpai!
Rin...
You can wake me up.
But, it's sweat!
Whether it's sweat or
whatever, it's fine.
Did you have a bad dream?
What's it like to die?
Daikichi, are you gonna die before me?
Sadness about Grandpa's death...
Anxiety over what would
happen if I died...
Fear of her own death...
She isn't able to sort these out one
by one, so she's all jumbled up.
Rin, everything will be fine
'til you're a young lady.
When will I start to be a young lady?
I mean everything will be fine
'til you're a middle-aged lady.
Until then, I am not gonna die!
Count on it!
Okay.
And don't worry about
wetting the bed either.
You'll be fine as long as you
go to the toilet before bedtime.
The toilet is scary!
I'll go with you at night.
And if you still have
an accident after that,
all we have to do is
change your pajamas.
Will you be mad?
It's nothing to be mad about, and
it's nothing to be laughed at.
Okay.
What'd you want to talk to me about?
I'm sorry this is so
sudden, Hidaka-san...
Um... This is out of the blue,
but please transfer me to a section
that doesn't require working overtime!
What? Kawachi... Are
you serious about this?
Totally serious!
I see. So that's what's
new in your life...
Personally, I think it's a real shame...
But I've got a kid, too.
Somehow, I'll try to
convince the section chief.
I'm sorry. But I really
appreciate your help.
You do know the people
under you will make a fuss.
I can't understand it!
Why did it have to be you, Kawachi-san?!
Can't you ask another relative?!
I can't tell him that I insisted
on taking her in myself.
And aren't there nursery schools
that'll keep the kids 'til late at night?!
I don't wanna work for anyone
but you, Kawachi-san!
Certainly, this is sudden...
But higher-ups often
make sudden transfers.
So don't make a mountain
out of a molehill!
But... I really am sorry.
Even without me, my section
will eventually get settled.
And they should be able
to shuffle people around.
If not, there's something
wrong with the organization.
But I can't let Rin go on like this!
I don't think...
My line of thinking isn't wrong...
Right?
Maybe...
Did you finish?
You want this much rice?
Yeah, that's perfect!
Admittance Guide
Towel, box lunch, slippers,
toothbrush, cup...
With your name on everything!
Futon?!
Oh, that's only for the babies...
All right!
Daikichi, hurry up!
Right now, I couldn't state
"This isn't a sacrifice"
without having it sound like a lie...
But I hope I will be able to think
that way some years from now.
A sunny early Sunday afternoon
Let's go somewhere today
It's the same road I'm used to traveling
But I can see it sparkling so bright
With the sun shining down its warmth
And you here by my side...
I'm already high, high, high
I feel like dashing out
Sing, la, la, la
My voice out to forever
I'm already high, high, high
Ride the dancing wind
Sing, la, la, la
My voice springs up
Rin, you have that same thing on
your hand towel and lunch box...
What is it?
Like a dog with huge ears...
It's not a dog!
It's Lop Ear!
Lop...? What's that?
A rabbit!
This isn't a little dog?
It's a rabbit!
Jeez!
Rin, let's go pee.
I already went!
Is that right?